The Killing of a Sacred Deer is a drama, thriller,
mystery film directed by Yorgos Lanthimos.
Steven Murphy is a renowned cardiovascular surgeon who presides over
a spotless household with his wife and two children.
Lurking at the margins of his idyllic suburban existence is Martin, a fatherless teen who
insinuates himself into the doctor's life in gradually unsettling ways.
Steven Murphy, played by Colin Farrell.
Anna Murphy, played by Nicole Kidman.
Martin Lang, played by Barry Keoghan.
Kim Murphy, played by Raffey Cassidy.
Bob Murphy, played by Sunny Suljic.
Matthew Williams, played by Bill Camp.
The Killing of a Sacred Deer is a 2017 absurdist psychological horror thriller art film directed and
co-produced by Yorgos Lanthimos, who also co-wrote the screenplay with Efthimis Filippou.
It stars Colin Farrell, Nicole Kidman, Barry Keoghan, Raffey
Cassidy, Sunny Suljic, Alicia Silverstone, and Bill Camp.
It follows a cardiac surgeon who introduces his family to a teenage boy with a
connection to his past, after which they mysteriously begin to fall ill.
The film had its world premiere at the 70th Cannes Film Festival on
22 May 2017, where it was awarded Best Screenplay.
It was theatrically released in Ireland and the United
Kingdom on 3 November 2017, by Curzon.
It grossed $10.7 million worldwide and received positive reviews from critics, who praised Lanthimos' direction, the
screenplay, cinematography, and performances of the cast (particularly those of Keoghan, Farrell, and Kidman).
At the 15th Irish Film & Television Awards, the film earned four
nominations, with Keoghan winning Best Supporting Actor.
It was nominated for Best Director, Best Screenwriter, and Best Actor (Farrell) at the 30th European Film Awards,
and for Best Supporting Male (Keoghan) and Best Cinematography at the 33rd Independent Spirit Awards.
The film explores themes of husband wife relationship,
hostage, psychopath, insanity, blackmail.
The tone is lighthearted and dark and emotional.